Bertie Charles Forbes Papers
Bertie Charles Forbes Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "A Wonderful Scotchman's Story and Advice - Robert Dollar," in The American Dream, John K.M. McCaffrey, ed., 1964; published material (Box 10)
    - "World - Famous After Many Defeats," Forbes Magazine, May 31, 1919 (Box 11)
    - Untitled
      - On Andrew Carnegie, Hearst's Magazine, typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Brotherhood of Man (with one page fragment), 189?; holograph revised, (Box 11)
      - On Cecil John Rhodes, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Charles Anceney, 1923; typescript revised, holograph (Box 11)
      - On Clarence Edward Groesbeck, Forbes Magazine, 1933; typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Clarence W. Barron, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Coleman Du Pont (Interview), typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Edward G. Acheson, draft A, holograph, typescript revised; draft B, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Elbridge Amos Stuart, Forbes Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On F. Wayland Ayer, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On George B. Cortelyou, Forbes Magazine, typescript revised (Box 11)
      - On George I. Cochran, Forbes Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On George M. Reynolds, typescript revised, holograph (Box 11)
      - On Gerard Swope, typescript copy annotated (Box 11)
      - On Henry L. Doherty, Hearst's Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On James B. Duke, typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On James Couzens, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On John D. Rockefeller, Cosmopolitan, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Joseph F. Sartori, typescript (Box 11)
      - On Money, McClure's Magazine, 1928; typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Philanthropy, Cosmopolitan Magazine, 1931; typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Robert A. Irvin, Forbes Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Robert Dollar, typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Robert Dollar, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Robert H. Treman, Forbes Magazine, draft A, holograph revised; draft B, typescript copy (Box 11)
      - On Samuel Zemurray, Forbes Magazine, 1938; typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Thomas A. Wilson, Hearst's Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Thomas W. Lamont, Forbes Magazine, typescript revised (Box 11)
      - On Waldorf - Astoria, 1938; draft A, typescript copy revised; raft B, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Wall Street, Cosmopolitan Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Walter P. Chrysler (incomplete), typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Walter C. Teagle, Forbes Magazine, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On Wendell L. Willkie, 1936; typescript revised (Box 11)
      - On Wigginton E. Creed, typescript copy revised (Box 11)
      - On William S. Knudsen, 1937; typescript copy (Box 11)
      - Writings in South African newspapers, 1900 and after; 28 items (Box 11)
  - Books and pamphlets
    - The Salesman's Diary, 1938 (Box 13)
      All other books and pamphlets previously in BOX 12 have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. There is no longer a BOX 12. Please refer to for a complete listing.
  - Magazine columns
    - Electrical Dealer
      - Manuscripts
        - On Being Busy, 1931; typescript copy (Box 13)
        - On Carefulness, 1931; typescript copy (Box 13)
        - On Cooperation, 1931; typescript copy (Box 13)
        - On Discord, undated; typescript copy (Box 13)
        - On Friends, 1931; typescript copy (Box 13)
        - On Playing Fair, 1931; typescript copy revised (Box 13)
        - On Reaching Goals, 1928; typescript copy (Box 13)
      - Printed material, 1928-1933 (Box 13)
    - Forbes Magazine
      - Manuscripts
        - "The Child's Pet Toy: Are We All Children?", Jan 25, 1919; typescript (Box 13)
        - "Do Things Go Like This For You Sometimes?", 1918; typescript (Box 13)
        - "Does This Experience Ever Come To You?", Sep 20, 1919; typescript (Box 13)
        - "Don't Consider Only the Cost", typescript copy (Box 13)
        - "Swope Points Way to Industry", typescript copy (Box 13)
        - "Touching Life at Many Points", Jun 28, 1919; typescript (Box 13)
        - Untitled
          - On Being Simple, 1926; typescript reproduction (Box 13)
          - On Senator Joseph McCarthy, 1954; holograph (Box 13)
    - Hearst's Magazine
      - Printed material
        - "Finance", 1912-1914 (Box 13)
    - Tea Man
      - Manuscripts
        - "Make Sales Rise in the Fall", draft A, typescript revised; draft B, typescript copy (Box 13)
        - "Make Summer a Hummer", typescript copy revised (Box 13)
        - "Recent Changes Strengthen Our Company", typescript copy (Box 13)
        - "To Sell More, Talk More About Savings", typescript copy revised (Box 13)
        - Untitled
          - On Goodwill, typescript copy (Box 13)
          - On Henry L. Jones, 1923; typescript annotated (Box 13)
          - On Inner Rewards (incomplete), typescript copy (Box 13)
          - On Salesmen, typescript copy revised (Box 13)
          - On Tact, typescript copy revised (Box 13)
      - Printed material, 1923-1924; undated (Box 13)
  - Newspaper columns
    - New York American
      - Manuscripts
        - Draft, typescript copy (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy, Feb 1925? (Box 13)
        - Draft fragment, typescript copy revised, Dec 27, 1932 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy, Oct 1934
    - New York Journal and American (result of merger of New York American and New York Journal)
      - Manuscripts
        - Draft, typescript revised, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Jun 26, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Jun 27, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Oct 1, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Nov 22, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Dec 6, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Dec 27, 1941 (Box 13)
        - Draft (by David Sarnoff), typescript copy, Feb 12, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy, Feb 24, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Mar 7, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy, Mar 12, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript revised reproduction, Apr 4, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Apr 9, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript revised, reproduction, May 1, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, May 13, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy, Jun 2, 1942 (Box 13)
        - Draft, typescript copy revised, Oct 4, 1943 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous extracts, typescript (Box 13)
    - New York American
      - Printed material
        - 1914-1929, undated, 12 folders (Box 13)
        - 1930-1936, 7 folders (Box 14)
    - New York Journal and American
      - Printed material
        - 1937, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - 1938-1942, 7 folders (Box 15)
  - Novels
    - Robert B. Ogilvy (incomplete and unpublished)
      - Chaps. 1-4, typescript revised (Box 16)
      - Chaps. 5-9, typescript revised, typescript copy revised (Box 16)
      - Chaps. 11, 14, 16, holograph revised, typescript copy (Box 16)
      - Draft revisions, chaps. 5, 9, typescript revised (Box 16)
      - Draft fragments, holograph (Box 16)
  - Short Stories
    - "Buchan's Greatest Sensation, or Turned Tables", 1900?; holograph revised (Box 16)
    - "The Clerk's Tale", 189?; holograph annotated (Box 16)
    - "Diary of a Young Lady," Peterhead Sentinel, Jan 21, 1911 (Box 16)
    - "The Hero of Poverty Flats," Forbes Magazine, 1917 (Box 16)
    - "The Honeymoon Couple", 19--?; printed material (Box 16)
    - "Lorenzo Lignwood's Marriage, or the Tables Turned", 19--?; holograph (Box 16)
    - "Queen of Flirts Abdicates", 19--?; printed material (Box 16)
    - "Vaulting Ambition, or a Novelist's Lovemaking", 189-?; holograph (Box 16)
    - "Vengeance: A Tragedy", 19--?; printed material (Box 16)
    - "A Woman's Sin: A Local Christmas Story", 19--?; printed material (Box 16)
    - Untitled, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Speeches
    - "America's Future Brightness", 1938; printed material (Box 16)
    - "The Book Industry Needs Overhauling"
      - Mimeo copy, 1952 (Box 16)
      - Publisher's Weekly, CLXI, 23, pp. 2351-2359, Jun 7, 1952 (Box 16)
    - "Facing the Forties", 1940; printed material (Box 16)
    - "The Future of the American Economic System", typescript revised (Box 16)
    - "How to Face the Future", 1938; printed material (Box 16)
    - "Most Critical Battle Won", 1938; draft, typescript copy; draft, typescript copy revised (transcript of address as given) (Box 16)
    - "The Outlook for 1940", printed material (Box 16)
    - "The South's Long Term Outlook", 1940; printed material (Box 16)
    - "They Ought to be Told", 1938; typescript revised (Box 16)
    - "Where Should America Go From Here", 1934; printed material (Box 16)
    - Untitled
      - On Business Journalism, typescript revised (Box 16)
      - On Investment, 1942?; typescript revised (Box 16)
      - On Outlook for 1936, typescript revised (Box 16)
      - On Outlook for 1939, 1938; typescript revised (Box 16)
      - On Presentation of Award to George F. Johnson, 1939; typescript (Box 16)
      - On Reception of Applause Award of Sales Executives Club, 1953; typescript (Box 16)
      - On Retail Business (incomplete), typescript revised (Box 16)
      - On Roosevelt Administration, 1938?; typescript revised (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newspaper articles and pamphlets, 1932-1942; printed material (Box 16)
    - Sketches, articles, and interviews (Vols. 6-9), 1900-1910?; printed material (Box 17)
- Miscellany
  - Rockefeller, John D., Random Reminiscences of Men and Events, typescript (Box 17)
  - Verity, George M.,"Response to B.C. Forbes' Presentation", 1940; typescript (Box 17)
  - Legacy Clippings/In Memoriam, 1971; printed material (Box 17)